Timothy Meier

1016 Beverly Drive, Wheeling IL 60090 Home: 847-650-6196 tmeier1218@yahoo.com

Summary

Switching Careers - Accomplished restaurant manager with 10+years proven ability to drive sales growth, reduce costs and build business relations. Many of the skills learned in the restaurant industry can be applied to the Computer field. You need to understand peoples wants and needs and provide good service. These experiences have all assisted me as I switch from the Restaurant Industry to Information Technology.

Education:

William Rainey Harper College, Palatine, IL

- Certificate of IT Software Development Certificate (2022)
- Associate of Applied Science: Food Service Management Certificate (2007)

Technical Skills:

| • HTML | • | Python | • Git |
|--------------|---|--------|----------|
| • CSS | • | MySQL | • GitHub |
| • JavaScript | • | SQL | |

Skills

| Organization and prioritization | Code Development |
|---|--|
| Debugging Programs | Service-oriented |
| Development and Training | Team contribution |
| Web Design | Effective multi-tasker |
| | |

Experience

Harper College, Palatine, IL

Teaching Instructor – Intro to Programming Sept 2020 to Present Assist students in learning programming skills, assist in debugging and developing their programming talents.

Uncle Julio's From Scratch Mexican Restaurant, Schaumburg, IL April 2019 to Current Assistant General Manager

- Run the floor and oversee all service standards are maintained by FOH team members
- Count all safe funds and bar money at beginning and end of shift
- Conduct line checks each shift when working as kitchen manager
- Maintain all food safety and quality
- Ensure food is delivered to the guests correctly and in a timely manner to ensure quality
- Write schedule for host department, oversee standards are upheld

Senior Manager

- Write the schedules for the Tasting Room
- Place orders twice a week for the wine delivery
- Place the order once a week for retail delivery
- Place liquor and beer orders weekly
- Conduct line checks with kitchen manager on shift
- Ensure staff follows Cooper's Hawk standards of service
- Current roles include Safety Manager and Training Manager

Cracker Barrel, Gurnee, IL

February 2015 to October 2015

Manager

- Write schedule for 85 employees
- Set up interviews for applicants, submit applicants for background checks, set up orientations
- Perform opening duties- count safe/register drawers, call production for kitchen staff to ensure proper food pars, follow up with kitchen staff to ensure pars are followed
- Ensure proper plating and portioning of food by kitchen team
- Place produce orders
- Conduct food inventory when scheduled with the food manager
- Continuous coaching of all team members to follow company's Guiding Principles and Absolutes
- Perform table touches to ensure satisfaction of all guests
- Assist on the retail side when needed

TGI Friday's (Multiple Locations)

July 2011 to December 2014

Bar/Kitchen/Service Manager

- Followed up with all training of all employees in restaurant to ensure timely completion
- Continued education of all employees when new food/drinks were implemented
- Coached employees during the shift when witnessing any deviation to company standards
- Maintained costs within set budget
- Responsible for building beverage sales while maintaining beverage cost
- Calculated inventory of all food, liquor, beer, wine, supplies and placed orders
- Development of team members
- Scheduled various departments